On the day we decided to depart,
we burned down our house.
Al, are you sure you're okay?
Yeah.
Leaving the village, I mean.
You don't have any regrets?
What are you talking about, Brother?
We decided to do this ourselves,
you know.
Actually, I think you're the one
who'll miss it more.
I'm all excited.
After all, I'm going to
become a State Alchemist! Me!
I feel the same way.
I'm going to get your body fixed, after all.
That's all right. You just need to worry about yourself.
Still, how do we get to be State Alchemists?
What kind of training does it take?
If they performed human transmutation
and escaped with their lives,
then I am more interested in them.
They could make fine State Alchemists.
Anyhow, we're going to go meet this Roy person.
Who knows? With talent as abundant as mine is,
it'll be a piece of cake!
Are you concerned about Winry?
Nothing we can do about it.
It's something those two have set their minds to.
I'm sure they'll be back
once they grow up.
Ed...
Al...
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Brother, do you know which train we're supposed to transfer to?
Yeah, it's coming at nine o'clock tomorrow morning.
Until then, let's get some sleep.
My bag!
Al!
That was a cinch!
Kids, huh? Off to bed with you now,
like good boys!
What the?!
Why don't you give it a rest there, instead?!
Nicely done!
That was something else!
Was that strange power just now alchemy?
Yeah.
To think that boys your age could be alchemists!
In these parts, Majhal would have to be the only alchemist around.
Majhal?
Sure. It's said that he has helped others out many times with his alchemy.
He's quite well respected.
Where is this person?
Ah, the next village over.
But you'd better not go there now.
There's this ominous rumor going around.
The rumor has it that dead people
are coming back to life in that village and attacking the villagers.
Do you know about this Majhal person, Brother?
No, but I saw that same name among all those letters of his.
You mean Dad's?
If I remember, he wrote about human transmutation.
If it's the same person,
it couldn't hurt to meet him, right?
Yeah! This seems like
it's going to be a good trip.
You sure seem unusually happy.
Well, we did catch that purse-snatcher, and everyone congratulated us.
I'm not sure how to say this,
but I'm happy that our alchemy was able to help others out.
Brother, are you all right?
No, I'm not!
That seat was hard and bounced around something awful.
You weren't bothered?
No.
I'll tell you what,
those are some incredible decorations.
Is there some festival going on?
Yikes! That one went toward the village!
What are you doing here?! This place is off-limits!
We're in the middle of
a fireworks rehearsal here!
F-Fireworks?
What are you talking about?!
The fireworks for the festival, of course!
I've never seen your faces before, have I?
What's with this guy?
He's got a strange outfit on!
Cut it out!
Let's get 'em. Should be fun.
We got 'em!
They're weak!
What are you doing?
Are you Majhal?
Wow, this is amazing.
An impressive spirit bonding.
H-He knows about me, Brother!
Just what you'd expect of Hohenheim's sons.
Apparently, you've inherited his great talent.
Now then, what can I do for you?
I can't very well turn down the
request of the sons of a dear friend.
We wanted to ask about the human transmutation you wrote about
in the letter you sent him.
Human transmutation?
You do know that it is
forbidden by law, right?
Maybe so...
But I want to return
Al's body back to normal.
The costs accompanying a human transmutation are altogether too great.
I know how you must feel,
but such an act is something that only God is allowed to perform.
Then why did you correspond with him
about human transmutation?
Youthful enthusiasm...
I guess you would call it.
Majhal-sama,
I made some rose jam,
if you'd like some.
I'm always grateful, Lebi.
Thanks.
Not at all.
Was there something else?
N-No. E-Excuse me.
Okay then, take care.
Come to mention it, there's a festival happening soon, right?
Yeah, the Requiem Festival.
The spirits of the dead are sent up
on fireworks, to return them to Heaven.
I've heard rumors about this village.
They say the dead are coming back to life
and attacking people here.
Does that have anything to do with it?
That's just a silly, baseless rumor.
My, my, I'm certainly having a lot of visitors today.
You!
Come on, Clause!
Majhal-sama, I'm really sorry about this.
Why do I have to apologize?!
It's their own fault for being so weak, isn't it?!
For boys, anyhow!
What?!
Brother, control yourself!
Clause, I know that you're upset about your sister's death.
But you were once
such a gentle little girl.
What would your late sister think if she saw you now?
Shut up!
Nobody knows how I feel!
My sister didn't just die—
she was killed when that lady came back to life!
Came back to life?
Clause!
Hey, wait up!
You guys are...
alchemists?
It's been half a year
since my sister died.
We didn't know the cause.
One of the villagers found her as they were passing by.
She looking like she was asleep, but she was dead.
And then, on the night of her funeral...
Clause...
K-Karin?!
Dad said that she was a woman who lived in this village a long time ago.
You know, right? The dead woman
came back to life and killed my sister!
And not only her!
It's all because of her!
Look, if you're alchemists, then avenge her for me!
I've asked Majhal-san,
but he won't do anything!
It's only natural that
Majhal-san won't do anything.
That's because your story is unbelievable.
Besides, I'm not too wild
about taking any revenge.
What are you talking about?
You guys are really just scared, aren't you?
And you call yourselves alchemists!
You're just a pipsqueak and an armor fanatic!
Pipsqueak?
Armor fanatic?
Don't you call me a pipsqueak!
I'm still going to grow up ultra-big!
You're a pipsqueak now, aren't you?
Pipsqueak! Pipsqueak! Ultra-hyper-super-pipsqueak!
Shut up!
What about you?! If you're a girl,
why don't you at least dress a little like one?!
None of your business!
Karin?
Yes, she did live here.
She made a living by raising flowers,
and she was a beautiful woman.
It must be twenty years ago now.
She succeeded in cultivating a very difficult blue rose.
Her smile at the time was simply...
However,
while she was riding in a carriage,
shipping her blue roses to the city...
she fell down along the
mountain roads and died there.
But they say that this Karin-san is attacking the villagers.
There's no way that could be.
The dead do not come back to life, after all.
And besides, even if she
were to come back to life,
it's inconceivable that she would attack the other villagers.
What do you think, Brother?
It's true, dead people
don't come back to life.
But supposing that someone were to perform a human transmutation...
The only person in this village who would be capable of that is Majhal-san.
Did you hear that just now?
Hear what?
We're really going to do it?
Yeah, we're going to catch this
Karin zombie with our own hands!
What, are you afraid?!
Someone else will probably get killed if this keeps up!
Y-Yeah, but...
Jeez, what are you doing, old lady?
I'm sorry.
I don't need your money, just go, would you?
You can't just stay here all day
Anyhow, we make our
move tonight. Got that?
over one bowl of soup.
Brother!
Wait up!
What's wrong, Al? Are you scared?
It's not that. There aren't really any zombies around, right?
Don't be ridiculous.
If the rumors are true, then it could only be by human transmutation.
It's worth checking out.
We did it!
We caught her!
You're hurting me, Al.
Oh, you guys...
O-Over there!
You... took my sister...
Clause!
That sound...
The alchemist Majhal...
Second-rate after all, I guess.
That's Majhal-sama for you!
Yeah, Majhal-sama, I knew you would put down that zombie for sure!
What's the matter, Brother?
That was neither a zombie
nor a human transmutation.
It was the same sound that I heard that other time.
Majhal-sama will be cross with you,
wandering around his residence on your own like this.
And what about you?
Brother!
Wh-What is all of this?
Brother, are you okay?
So, you're awake?
It appears that you've seen something that you shouldn't have seen.
Yeah, I saw. The identity of that zombie, that is.
This is your doing!
Yes, spirit bonding.
I take a mannequin that is the perfect likeness of Karin and bond one of the village girls to it.
By doing so, they were supposed to resemble a living Karin.
But you failed!
Spirits do not tend to bond to vessels that are unlike them.
You may think they are bonded,
but ordinarily, they are not functional.
There were even those who
slipped out of here on their own
and wandered around the village.
Do you realize what you've done?!
Why the hell would you do this?!
Karin was the only woman I ever loved.
No matter how many years pass since Karin's death, my scars will not heal.
I made up my mind
that I would bring Karin
back to life through alchemy.
However, it was impossible for me to perform human transmutation.
That being the case, I wanted to at least create something that was close to Karin.
That's what I thought.
You're sick!
No! I just love Karin!
You're going to assist me now,
in a spiritual bonding for my love.
No way.
Indeed. You're just as stubborn as Hohenheim was.
Um, I wanted to thank you...
You foolish girl.
Stop!
Please stop, Majhal-sama!
End this already!
Shut up! This has nothing to do with you!
Hey, do something, fast!
Just a little more...
A blue rose?
Receive this girl's spirit and smile
upon me this time without fail, Karin!
No! Stop!
Stop, Majhal!
You don't understand a thing!
What you were seeking
has been right next to you!
What are you talking about?
Karin-san didn't die!
After the accident, she lost her memory and lived from then on someplace else!
And then, twenty years later,
Karin-san got her memory back and came straight back to you.
But you didn't realize it was her!
Majhal...
Impossible...
Are you saying that this woman is Karin?
Karin was more beautiful than any other woman!
Like a rose!
Face reality!
Flowers wither.
But Karin-san's feelings
toward you have not changed!
Silence! Say one more word,
and I'll kill you!
Majhal! Majhal!
N-No...
You are not... Karin.
There's no way... you could be Karin.
What are you moping about, Al?
I was thinking that alchemy can also delude people.
Yeah, you're right.
Hey!
I'm sorry about everything.
You really are terrific alchemists, huh?
That may be so,
but who are you?
Don't tell me you're... Clause?!
What do you mean, "Ehhh!"?
You definitely look better in those clothes!
See ya!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 5: "Dash! Automail"
You wanted power too, didn't you?
That's what the man with the mechanical arm said to me.